Fábio Gabriel de Magalhães

Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil +55 51 98216 1084 fmagalhaes@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/fabiogm

ABOUT

Software engineer with over eight years of experience. Pragmatic, always striving to keep balance between technical excellence and business value delivery. Worked on projects ranging from greenfield applications to large legacy systems, across diverse industries like retail, healthcare and banking. Currently working as a back-end engineer and leading a small team.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, Python, Ruby, Javascript, Node.js, SQL, R, C, C++ Databases, Data Stores & Tools: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Hive, HBase

Operating Systems & Platforms: OSX, Linux, Windows, Unix, Pivotal Cloud Foundry, Amazon Web Services, Heroku

Methodologies: Agile software development, lean practices, test-driven development, behavior-driven development

EXPERIENCE

Consultant Developer ThoughtWorks

2014-Present

- The Gap, Inc. (July 2016 present) created an ecosystem of applications used by the allocator managers of the brands to allocate products to stores and control product life-cycles across several markets around the world. The web UI presents users with several attributes of each product and helps in the decision making process by presenting sales forecast for products. Event-driven microservices architecture, with Java services communicating via REST APIs and RabbitMQ for asynchronous messaging. Deployed to an on-premises Pivotal Cloud Foundry environment. The allocation UI is an AngularJS Single Page Application.
- The Gap, Inc. (July 2015 June 2016) developed a large scale order routing system responsible for routing e-commerce orders. The system also helps remove stranded inventory from stores, making more products available to online customers and increasing profits. Backend application using Java.
- Leading US healthcare improvement company (November 2014 July 2015) created a web application for reconciliation and contract revenue forecasting used by contract managers. The system made contract revenue more predictable enabling contract managers to take corrective actions sooner. The system was deployed to Amazon Web Services and was composed of a web application using AngularJS, a backend for frontend application implemented in Java and a predictive model implemented in Python.
- Large US online marketing and advertising provider (July October 2014) implemented a control panel for advertising campaign managers that aids the creation of more effective campaigns in order to optimize user's marketing budgets. Single Page Application using AngularJS and a backend for frontend implemented in Ruby on Rails.
- Large Brazilian retailer (May Jun 2014) developed a proof of concept of a business intelligence system including data ingestion, data transformation and stock metrics reporting using Hive in the cloud (Amazon EMR). Interface with legacy systems using Ruby and Oracle 11g.

- Developed websites using Python and Javascript
- Developed a small scale CMS using Python running on Google App Engine platform
- Developed a prototype for a platform game using Python and PyGame

Software Engineer

2009 - 2011

Tools and Technologies

- Worked in the design and implementation of banking software for ATMs, using C++ (backend), HTML and Javascript(UI). Acted as a contractor for a Brazilian company which is the largest player in the segment of technologies and services for business and electronic transactions.
- Worked in the design, implementation and maintenance of firmware for storage controllers using C. Also contributed in the design, implementation and maintenance of test infrastructure using C++ under Unix. Acted as a contractor for a multinational company in a demographically distributed team.

Software Developer

2008 - 2009

Datum TI

• Worked in the design, implementation and maintenance of banking software (point of sale automation). Employed C++ for branch server and Visual Basic for points of sale on a service-oriented architecture over DCOM.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Applied Mathematics Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul (UFRGS), Brazil 2012-2016

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Universidade do Vale do Rio dos Sinos (Unisinos), Brazil 2006-2010 (Not graduated)

Technician, Information Systems Colégio São Luís, Brazil 2001-2004

CONTINUING EDUCATION

Statistical Inference, Practical Machine Learning, Regression Models, Reproducible Research, R Programming, Getting and Cleaning Data, The Data Scientist's Toolbox, Exploratory Data Analysis

(Courses composing John Hopkins University online specialization in Data Science, 2014-2017)

Development of ARM7 firmware using C language (2010)

Introduction to CMMI (2008)

Italian Language, modules Basic I and II (2007)

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

reading, musical composition, Mandarin Chinese

LANGUAGES

Portuguese (Native), English (Full professional proficiency)